[
    {
        "ID" : 1,
        "Name" : "Question 1",
        "Question" : "Which module gives control of the CPU to the process selected by the short-term scheduler?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Dispatcher"},
            {"B" : "Interrupt"},
            {"C" : "Scheduler"},
            {"D" : "None Of The Mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Dispatcher"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 2,
        "Name" : "Question 2",
        "Question" : "The processes that are residing in main memory and are ready and waiting to execute are kept on a list called _____",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Job Queue"},
            {"B" : "Ready Queue"},
            {"C" : "Execution Queue"},
            {"D" : "Process Queue"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Ready Queue"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 3,
        "Name" : "Question 3",
        "Question" : "The interval from the time of submission of a process to the time of completion is termed as ________",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Waiting Time"},
            {"B" : "Turnaround Time"},
            {"C" : "Response Time"},
            {"D" : "Throughput"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Turnaround Time"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 4,
        "Name" : "Question 4",
        "Question" : "Which scheduling algorithm allocates the CPU first to the process that requests the CPU first?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "First-come, First-served Scheduling"},
            {"B" : "Shortest Job Scheduling"},
            {"C" : "Priority Scheduling"},
            {"D" : "None Of The Mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "First-come, First-served Scheduling"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 5,
        "Name" : "Question 5",
        "Question" : "In priority scheduling algorithm ____________",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "CPU is allocated to the process with highest priority"},
            {"B" : "CPU is allocated to the process with lowest priority"},
            {"C" : "Equal priority processes can not be scheduled"},
            {"D" : "None of the mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "CPU is allocated to the process with highest priority"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 6,
        "Name" : "Question 6",
        "Question" : "In priority scheduling algorithm, when a process arrives at the ready queue, its priority is compared with the priority of __________",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "All Processes"},
            {"B" : "Currently Running Process"},
            {"C" : "Parent Process"},
            {"D" : "Init Process"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Currently Running Process"
    },
    
    {
        "ID" : 7,
        "Name" : "Question 7",
        "Question" : "Which algorithm is defined in Time quantum?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Shortest Job Scheduling Algorithm"},
            {"B" : "Round Robin Scheduling Algorithm"},
            {"C" : "Priority Scheduling Algorithm"},
            {"D" : "Multilevel Queue Scheduling Algorithm"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Round Robin Scheduling Algorithm"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 8,
        "Name" : "Question 8",
        "Question" : "Process are classified into different groups in __________",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Shortest Job Scheduling Algorithm"},
            {"B" : "Round Robin Scheduling Algorithm"},
            {"C" : "Priority Scheduling Algorithm"},
            {"D" : "Multilevel Queue Scheduling Algorithm"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Multilevel Queue Scheduling Algorithm"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 9,
        "Name" : "Question 9",
        "Question" : "In multilevel feedback scheduling algorithm ____________",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "A process can move to a different classified ready queue"},
            {"B" : "Classification of ready queue is permanent"},
            {"C" : "Processes are not classified into groups"},
            {"D" : "None of the mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "A process can move to a different classified ready queue"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 10,
        "Name" : "Question 10",
        "Question" : "Which one of the following can not be scheduled by the kernel?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Kernel Level Thread"},
            {"B" : "User Level Thread"},
            {"C" : "Process"},
            {"D" : "None Of The Mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "User Level Thread"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 11,
        "Name" : "Question 11",
        "Question" : "Who developed the idea of a stored program computer and modern computer architecture?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "John Von Neumann"},
            {"B" : "Bill Gates"},
            {"C" : "Steve Jobs"},
            {"D" : "Tim Berners-Lee"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "John Von Neumann"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 12,
        "Name" : "Question 12",
        "Question" : "The idea developed in 1945 by Von Neumann of a computer holding both programs and the data used by the programs in memory is called the _______?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Memory Program System"},
            {"B" : "Stored Program Concept"},
            {"C" : "Stored Memory Concept"},
            {"D" : "Stored Memory Program"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Stored Program Concept"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 13,
        "Name" : "Question 13",
        "Question" : "What connects the processor and memory?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Network Interface Card (NIC)"},
            {"B" : "Cache"},
            {"C" : "Buses"},
            {"D" : "Control Unit"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Buses"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 14,
        "Name" : "Question 14",
        "Question" : "What are the 3 parts of the Von Neumann computer architecture?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Memory (CU & ALU), Hard Disk & Input/Output"},
            {"B" : "Processor, RAM & ROM"},
            {"C" : "Processor, RAM & Hard Disk"},
            {"D" : "Processor (CU & ALU), Memory Unit & Input/Output"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Processor (CU & ALU), Memory Unit & Input/Output"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 15,
        "Name" : "Question 15",
        "Question" : "What are the two main parts of the processor?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Control Unit & Arithmetic Logic Unit"},
            {"B" : "RAM & ROM"},
            {"C" : "RAM & Cache"},
            {"D" : "Control Unit & Cache"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Control Unit & Arithmetic Logic Unit"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 16,
        "Name" : "Question 16",
        "Question" : "Which of these is not a bus within the computer?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Address Bus"},
            {"B" : "I/O Bus"},
            {"C" : "Data Bus"},
            {"D" : "Control"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "I/O Bus"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 17,
        "Name" : "Question 17",
        "Question" : "Which of these buses is bi-directional?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Address Bus"},
            {"B" : "Control Bus"},
            {"C" : "Data Bus"},
            {"D" : "Cache Bus"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Data Bus"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 18,
        "Name" : "Question 18",
        "Question" : "Which bus is used to send read and write signals to a storage device such as a HDD?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Data Bus"},
            {"B" : "Address Bus"},
            {"C" : "I/O Bus"},
            {"D" : "Control Bus"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Control Bus"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 19,
        "Name" : "Question 19",
        "Question" : "What is the location of where data can be found in the computer memory is called?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Address"},
            {"B" : "Coordinates"},
            {"C" : "Register"},
            {"D" : "Cache"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Address"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 20,
        "Name" : "Question 20",
        "Question" : "What is the small high speed storage areas within the memory and processor are known as?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Addresses"},
            {"B" : "Registers"},
            {"C" : "Cache"},
            {"D" : "Buses"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Registers"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 21,
        "Name" : "Question 21",
        "Question" : "The MDR, MAR, PC & CIR are all examples of _____",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Buses"},
            {"B" : "Control Units"},
            {"C" : "Registers"},
            {"D" : "Addresses"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Registers"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 22,
        "Name" : "Question 22",
        "Question" : "Which of the following is not a register?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "MAR"},
            {"B" : "MDR"},
            {"C" : "PC"},
            {"D" : "CU"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "CU"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 23,
        "Name" : "Question 23",
        "Question" : "What does the DDR in DDR SDRAM stand for?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Double Data Rate"},
            {"B" : "Dynamic Data Rate"},
            {"C" : "Double Data Repitition"},
            {"D" : "Dynamic Data Repitition"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Double Data Rate"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 24,
        "Name" : "Question 24",
        "Question" : "The full name for the RAM used in modern computers is SDRAM, what does the SD stand for?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Synchronous Data"},
            {"B" : "Synchronous Dynamic"},
            {"C" : "Secure Digital"},
            {"D" : "Synchronous Digital"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Synchronous Dynamic"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 25,
        "Name" : "Question 25",
        "Question" : "Where are the Data and Instructions in use stored?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Processor"},
            {"B" : "Embedded System"},
            {"C" : "Hard Disk Drive"},
            {"D" : "Main Memory (RAM)"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Main Memory (RAM)"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 26,
        "Name" : "Question 26",
        "Question" : "Processors have a speed measured in ______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Hertz (Hz)"},
            {"B" : "Bits"},
            {"C" : "Bytes"},
            {"D" : "Seconds"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Hertz (Hz)"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 27,
        "Name" : "Question 27",
        "Question" : "What does not affect the performance of the computer?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Clock Speed"},
            {"B" : "Number Of Cores"},
            {"C" : "Cache Size"},
            {"D" : "The Number Of Instructions In The Program"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "The Number Of Instructions In The Program"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 28,
        "Name" : "Question 28",
        "Question" : "If the number of cores goes up from 2 to 4, what is the exact effect on performance?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Performance decreases"},
            {"B" : "The maximum number of instructions executed per second doubles"},
            {"C" : "The maximum number of instructions executed per second quadruples"},
            {"D" : "The maximum number of instructions executed per second is halved"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "The maximum number of instructions executed per second doubles"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 29,
        "Name" : "Question 29",
        "Question" : "If the processing speed goes up from 1GHZ to 4GHZ, what is the exact effect on the performance of the computer?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "The maximum number of instructions executed per second doubles"},
            {"B" : "The maximum number of instructions executed per second quadruples"},
            {"C" : "The maximum number of instructions executed per second is halved"},
            {"D" : "The maximum number of instructions executed per second is quartered"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "The maximum number of instructions executed per second quadruples"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 30,
        "Name" : "Question 30",
        "Question" : "Which is an example of an Embedded System",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Laptops"},
            {"B" : "Tablets"},
            {"C" : "PCs"},
            {"D" : "Washing Machine"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Washing Machine"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 31,
        "Name" : "Question 31",
        "Question" : "What is the part of a processor in which instructions are executed known as?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Core"},
            {"B" : "Centre"},
            {"C" : "Execution"},
            {"D" : "Instruction Centre"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Core"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 32,
        "Name" : "Question 32",
        "Question" : "What acts as an intermediary between the processor and the Main Memory (RAM)?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Bus"},
            {"B" : "User"},
            {"C" : "Cache"},
            {"D" : "Clock"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Cache"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 33,
        "Name" : "Question 33",
        "Question" : "What is held in cache?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "All of the programming instructions"},
            {"B" : "Commonly used instructions and data"},
            {"C" : "Instructions that have been processed"},
            {"D" : "Data that hasn’t been used for a long time"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Commonly used instructions and data"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 34,
        "Name" : "Question 34",
        "Question" : "What does Firmware refer to?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Any hardware that can’t easily break"},
            {"B" : "A combination of hardware and software"},
            {"C" : "A type of software that is updated to make a computer work better"},
            {"D" : "Hardware used in kitchens"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "A combination of hardware and software"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 35,
        "Name" : "Question 35",
        "Question" : "What component holds the address of the next instruction?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Memory Address Register"},
            {"B" : "Memory Data Register"},
            {"C" : "Program Counter"},
            {"D" : "Accumulator"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Memory Address Register"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 36,
        "Name" : "Question 36",
        "Question" : "Results of calculations are held in this register",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Memory Address Register"},
            {"B" : "Memory Data Register"},
            {"C" : "Program Counter"},
            {"D" : "Accumulator"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Accumulator"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 37,
        "Name" : "Question 37",
        "Question" : "This holds the instruction/data temporarily after it is brought to the processor from the main memory",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Memory Address Register"},
            {"B" : "Memory Data Register"},
            {"C" : "Program Counter"},
            {"D" : "Accumulator"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Memory Data Register"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 38,
        "Name" : "Question 38",
        "Question" : "This holds the number of the current instruction being worked on",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Memory Address Register"},
            {"B" : "Memory Data Register"},
            {"C" : "Program Counter"},
            {"D" : "Accumulator"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Program Counter"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 39,
        "Name" : "Question 39",
        "Question" : "This would perform an operation including the word “And”",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Arithmetic Logic Unit"},
            {"B" : "Accumulator"},
            {"C" : "Cache"},
            {"D" : "Control Unit"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Arithmetic Logic Unit"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 40,
        "Name" : "Question 40",
        "Question" : "This would perform an operation such as 5+8",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Cache"},
            {"B" : "Control Unit"},
            {"C" : "Accumulator"},
            {"D" : "Arithmetic Logic Unit"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Arithmetic Logic Unit"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 41,
        "Name" : "Question 41",
        "Question" : "This would reduce the number of memory/processor transfers",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Arithmetic Logic Unit"},
            {"B" : "Cache"},
            {"C" : "Control Unit"},
            {"D" : "Accumulator"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Cache"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 42,
        "Name" : "Question 42",
        "Question" : "This doesn’t happen during the Fetch part of the cycle",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Address Bus is used"},
            {"B" : "Program Counter increments by one"},
            {"C" : "Arithmetic operations are performed"},
            {"D" : "Main Memory is addressed"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Arithmetic operations are performed"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 43,
        "Name" : "Question 43",
        "Question" : "This doesn’t happen during the Decode / Execute part of the cycle",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Current Instruction is held in the Current Instruction Register (CIR)"},
            {"B" : "Results are held in the Accumulator"},
            {"C" : "Status Register updated"},
            {"D" : "Instructions are transferred from Main Memory"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Instructions are transferred from Main Memory"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 44,
        "Name" : "Question 44",
        "Question" : "What is held in ROM?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Data currently in use"},
            {"B" : "Bootstrap Loader"},
            {"C" : "Instructions frequently used"},
            {"D" : "Operating System"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Bootstrap Loader"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 45,
        "Name" : "Question 45",
        "Question" : "It carries the address of the next instruction that will be fetched",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Address Bus"},
            {"B" : "Data Bus"},
            {"C" : "Control Bus"},
            {"D" : "System Bus"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Address Bus"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 46,
        "Name" : "Question 46",
        "Question" : "Which component generates addresses?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Processor"},
            {"B" : "Main Memory"},
            {"C" : "Control Unit"},
            {"D" : "Secondary Storage"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Processor"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 47,
        "Name" : "Question 47",
        "Question" : "What is transferred down the data bus?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Data only"},
            {"B" : "Addresses only"},
            {"C" : "Data and Instructions"},
            {"D" : "Data, Instructions and Addresses"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Data and Instructions"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 48,
        "Name" : "Question 48",
        "Question" : "What is the purpose of the accumulator?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "To perform arithmetic operations"},
            {"B" : "To hold the results of a calculation"},
            {"C" : "To hold the accumulation of instructions that have happened"},
            {"D" : "None of the mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "To hold the results of a calculation"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 49,
        "Name" : "Question 49",
        "Question" : "The ______ format is usually used to store data",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Binary-coded Decimal (BCD)"},
            {"B" : "Decimal"},
            {"C" : "Hexadecimal"},
            {"D" : "Octal"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Binary-coded Decimal (BCD)"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 50,
        "Name" : "Question 50",
        "Question" : "A source program is usually in _______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Assembly language"},
            {"B" : "Machine level language"},
            {"C" : "High-level language"},
            {"D" : "Natural language"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "High-level language"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 51,
        "Name" : "Question 51",
        "Question" : "The small extremely fast, RAM’s are called as _______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Cache"},
            {"B" : "Heaps"},
            {"C" : "Accumulators"},
            {"D" : "Stacks"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Cache"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 52,
        "Name" : "Question 52",
        "Question" : "The ALU makes use of _______ to store the intermediate results",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Accumulators"},
            {"B" : "Registers"},
            {"C" : "Heaps"},
            {"D" : "Stacks"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Accumulators"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 53,
        "Name" : "Question 53",
        "Question" : "The control unit controls other units by generating __________",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Control Signals"},
            {"B" : "Timing Signals"},
            {"C" : "Transfer Signals"},
            {"D" : "Command Signals"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Timing Signals"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 54,
        "Name" : "Question 54",
        "Question" : "To reduce the memory access time we generally make use of ______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Heaps"},
            {"B" : "Higher capacity RAM’s"},
            {"C" : "SDRAM’s"},
            {"D" : "Cache’s"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Cache’s"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 55,
        "Name" : "Question 55",
        "Question" : "______ is generally used to increase the apparent size of physical memory",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Secondary Memory"},
            {"B" : "Virtual Memory"},
            {"C" : "Hard-disk"},
            {"D" : "Disks"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Virtual Memory"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 56,
        "Name" : "Question 56",
        "Question" : "The time delay between two successive initiations of memory operation _______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Memory Access Time"},
            {"B" : "Memory Search Time"},
            {"C" : "Memory Cycle Time"},
            {"D" : "Instruction Delay"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Memory Cycle Time"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 57,
        "Name" : "Question 57",
        "Question" : "______ are used to overcome the difference in data transfer speeds of various devices",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Speed Enhancing Circuitry"},
            {"B" : "Bridge Circuits"},
            {"C" : "Multiple Buses"},
            {"D" : "Buffer Registers"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Buffer Registers"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 58,
        "Name" : "Question 58",
        "Question" : "The decoded instruction is stored in ______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Instruction Register (IR)"},
            {"B" : "PC"},
            {"C" : "Registers"},
            {"D" : "Memory Data Register (MDR)"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Instruction Register (IR)"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 59,
        "Name" : "Question 59",
        "Question" : "Which registers can interact with the secondary storage?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Memory Address Register (MAR)"},
            {"B" : "PC"},
            {"C" : "Instruction Register (IR)"},
            {"D" : "Memory Data Register (MDR)"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Memory Address Register (MAR)"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 60,
        "Name" : "Question 60",
        "Question" : "During the execution of a program which gets initialized first?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Memory Data Register (MDR)"},
            {"B" : "Instruction Register (IR)"},
            {"C" : "PC"},
            {"D" : "Memory Address Register (MAR)"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "PC"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 61,
        "Name" : "Question 61",
        "Question" : "Which of the register/s of the processor is/are connected to Memory Bus?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "PC"},
            {"B" : "Memory Address Register (MAR)"},
            {"C" : "Instruction Register (IR)"},
            {"D" : "Both PC and MAR"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Memory Address Register (MAR)"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 62,
        "Name" : "Question 62",
        "Question" : "The internal components of the processor are connected by _______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Processor Intra-connectivity Circuitry"},
            {"B" : "Processor Bus"},
            {"C" : "Memory Bus"},
            {"D" : "Rambus"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Processor Bus"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 63,
        "Name" : "Question 63",
        "Question" : "During the execution of the instructions, a copy of the instructions is placed in the ______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Register"},
            {"B" : "RAM"},
            {"C" : "System Heap"},
            {"D" : "Cache"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Cache"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 64,
        "Name" : "Question 64",
        "Question" : "A processor performing fetch or decoding of different instruction during the execution of another instruction is called ______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Super-scaling"},
            {"B" : "Pipe-lining"},
            {"C" : "Parallel Computation"},
            {"D" : "None Of The Mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Pipe-lining"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 65,
        "Name" : "Question 65",
        "Question" : "The clock rate of the processor can be improved by _________",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Improving the IC technology of the logic circuits"},
            {"B" : "Reducing the amount of processing done in one step"},
            {"C" : "By using the overclocking method"},
            {"D" : "All Of The Mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "All Of The Mentioned"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 66,
        "Name" : "Question 66",
        "Question" : "An optimizing Compiler does _________",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Better compilation of the given piece of code"},
            {"B" : "Takes advantage of the type of processor and reduces its process time"},
            {"C" : "Does better memory management"},
            {"D" : "None of the mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Takes advantage of the type of processor and reduces its process time"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 67,
        "Name" : "Question 67",
        "Question" : "The ultimate goal of a compiler is to ________",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Reduce the clock cycles for a programming task"},
            {"B" : "Reduce the size of the object code"},
            {"C" : "Be versatile"},
            {"D" : "Be able to detect even the smallest of errors"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Reduce the clock cycles for a programming task"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 68,
        "Name" : "Question 68",
        "Question" : "When Performing a looping operation, the instruction gets stored in the ______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Registers"},
            {"B" : "Cache"},
            {"C" : "System Heap"},
            {"D" : "System Stack"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Cache"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 69,
        "Name" : "Question 69",
        "Question" : "CISC stands for _______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Complete Instruction Sequential Compilation"},
            {"B" : "Computer Integrated Sequential Compiler"},
            {"C" : "Complex Instruction Set Computer"},
            {"D" : "Complex Instruction Sequential Compilation"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Complex Instruction Set Computer"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 70,
        "Name" : "Question 70",
        "Question" : "During the transfer of data between the processor and memory we use ______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Cache"},
            {"B" : "Translation Lookaside Buffer (TLB)"},
            {"C" : "Buffers"},
            {"D" : "Registers"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Registers"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 71,
        "Name" : "Question 71",
        "Question" : "What is the CPU is responsible for?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Allocating memory locations to save files"},
            {"B" : "All storage methods in your system"},
            {"C" : "The monitoring of the computer's temperature"},
            {"D" : "All of a computer’s processing"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "All of a computer’s processing"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 72,
        "Name" : "Question 72",
        "Question" : "When using the Von Neumann architecture computer programs and the data the programs are using are stored in the same memory, why?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "To save memory"},
            {"B" : "To speed up the processing time"},
            {"C" : "To complicate the process"},
            {"D" : "To make it easier for people to save things"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "To speed up the processing time"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 73,
        "Name" : "Question 73",
        "Question" : "Which of the following is a characteristic of Random Access Memory (RAM)?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Memory used to store running programs and to manipulate data"},
            {"B" : "Main memory as this is the memory we use first"},
            {"C" : "A source of memory to store your files such as your coursework"},
            {"D" : "Used to store boot up instructions for loading the OS"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Memory used to store running programs and to manipulate data"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 74,
        "Name" : "Question 74",
        "Question" : "What is the Control Unit?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "The unit which allows the user to control the interface"},
            {"B" : "The unit that holds memory locations of data"},
            {"C" : "The control unit is a component of a computer's central processing unit that directs the operation of the processor"},
            {"D" : "The unit which effects the setting up peripheral devices"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "The control unit is a component of a computer's central processing unit that directs the operation of the processor"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 75,
        "Name" : "Question 75",
        "Question" : "Which of the following does the Arithmetic Logic Unit not do?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Arithmetic Operations"},
            {"B" : "Shift Operations"},
            {"C" : "Shift Data Flow"},
            {"D" : "Logical Operations"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Shift Data Flow"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 76,
        "Name" : "Question 76",
        "Question" : "What is the Clock speed in relation to the CPU?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "The mbps where the computer sends data"},
            {"B" : "A physical flow of electricity within the computer"},
            {"C" : "The operating speed of the clock within the computer"},
            {"D" : "The operating speed of a computer or its microprocessor, expressed in cycles per second (megahertz)"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "The operating speed of a computer or its microprocessor, expressed in cycles per second (megahertz)"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 77,
        "Name" : "Question 77",
        "Question" : "Which of these is true about the greater a CPU's clock speed?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "The quicker the CPU can cycle through instructions and complete tasks"},
            {"B" : "The more detailed the completion of tasks are done"},
            {"C" : "The slower the CPU handles instructions"},
            {"D" : "The quicker the main memory and secondary memory exchange data"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "The quicker the CPU can cycle through instructions and complete tasks"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 78,
        "Name" : "Question 78",
        "Question" : "What impact does having more cores have on a CPU?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Less cores are better for faster processing"},
            {"B" : "More cores means that the CPU does not need a heat sink"},
            {"C" : "The more cores, the more instructions can be processed at one time"},
            {"D" : "The more cores, the slower instructions are processed"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "The more cores, the more instructions can be processed at one time"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 79,
        "Name" : "Question 79",
        "Question" : "What is Cache memory?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "It is the largest group of memory in the hard disk"},
            {"B" : "It is a large piece of memory accessed by the CPU"},
            {"C" : "It is the place that instructions hardly used are stored"},
            {"D" : "It is a small amount of very fast, expensive memory in the CPU"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "It is a small amount of very fast, expensive memory in the CPU"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 80,
        "Name" : "Question 80",
        "Question" : "What is Level 1 Cache?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Extremely fast but small (between 2-64KB), located very close to the processor"},
            {"B" : "The lowest part of the memory triangle"},
            {"C" : "Extremely slow and large in memory (2-64GB) and located far from the processor"},
            {"D" : "Extremely fast but large in memory (2-64GB) , located very close to the processor"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Extremely fast but small (between 2-64KB), located very close to the processor"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 81,
        "Name" : "Question 81",
        "Question" : "Which type of memory sits in the main memory?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "RAM (Random Access Memory)"},
            {"B" : "Solid State Disk"},
            {"C" : "Flash Memory"},
            {"D" : "Hard Drive"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "RAM (Random Access Memory)"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 82,
        "Name" : "Question 82",
        "Question" : "What is computer architecture?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "A set of categories and methods that specify the functioning, organisation, and implementation of computer systems"},
            {"B" : "A set of principles and methods that specify the functioning, organisation, and implementation of computer systems"},
            {"C" : "A set of functions and methods that specify the functioning, organisation, and implementation of computer systems"},
            {"D" : "None of the mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "A set of principles and methods that specify the functioning, organisation, and implementation of computer systems"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 83,
        "Name" : "Question 83",
        "Question" : "What is computer organization?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "The structure and behaviour of a computer system as observed by the user"},
            {"B" : "The structure of a computer system as observed by the developer"},
            {"C" : "The structure and behaviour of a computer system as observed by the developer"},
            {"D" : "All of the mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "The structure and behaviour of a computer system as observed by the user"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 84,
        "Name" : "Question 84",
        "Question" : "Which of the architecture is power efficient?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "RISC"},
            {"B" : "ISA"},
            {"C" : "IANA"},
            {"D" : "CISC"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "RISC"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 85,
        "Name" : "Question 85",
        "Question" : "The IA-32 system follows which of the following design?",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "CISC"},
            {"B" : "SIMD"},
            {"C" : "RISC"},
            {"D" : "None Of The Mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "CISC"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 86,
        "Name" : "Question 86",
        "Question" : "In CISC architecture most of the complex instructions are stored in _____",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "CMOS"},
            {"B" : "Register"},
            {"C" : "Transistors"},
            {"D" : "Diodes"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Transistors"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 87,
        "Name" : "Question 87",
        "Question" : "Both the CISC and RISC architectures have been developed to reduce the ______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Time Delay"},
            {"B" : "Semantic Gap"},
            {"C" : "Cost"},
            {"D" : "All Of The Mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Semantic Gap"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 88,
        "Name" : "Question 88",
        "Question" : "The reason for the cells to lose their state over time is ________",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Use of Shift registers"},
            {"B" : "The lower voltage levels"},
            {"C" : "Usage of capacitors to store the charge"},
            {"D" : "None of the mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Usage of capacitors to store the charge"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 89,
        "Name" : "Question 89",
        "Question" : "n order to read multiple bytes of a row at the same time, we make use of ______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Memory Extension"},
            {"B" : "Cache"},
            {"C" : "Shift Register"},
            {"D" : "Latch"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Latch"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 90,
        "Name" : "Question 90",
        "Question" : "The difference in the address and data connection between DRAM’s and SDRAM’s is _______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "The requirement of more address lines in SDRAM’s"},
            {"B" : "The usage of a buffer in SDRAM’s"},
            {"C" : "The usage of more number of pins in SDRAM’s"},
            {"D" : "None of the mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "The usage of a buffer in SDRAM’s"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 91,
        "Name" : "Question 91",
        "Question" : "The data is transferred over the RAMBUS as _______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Blocks"},
            {"B" : "Swing voltages"},
            {"C" : "Bits"},
            {"D" : "Packets"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Swing voltages"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 92,
        "Name" : "Question 92",
        "Question" : "The memory devices which are similar to EEPROM but differ in the cost effectiveness is ______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "CMOS"},
            {"B" : "Memory Sticks"},
            {"C" : "Blue-ray Devices"},
            {"D" : "Flash Memory"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Flash Memory"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 93,
        "Name" : "Question 93",
        "Question" : "The drawback of building a large memory with DRAM is _________",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "The slow speed of operation"},
            {"B" : "The large cost factor"},
            {"C" : "The inefficient memory organisation"},
            {"D" : "All of the mentioned"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "The slow speed of operation"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 94,
        "Name" : "Question 94",
        "Question" : "The bit used to signify that the cache location is updated is ________",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Flag Bit"},
            {"B" : "Reference Bit"},
            {"C" : "Update Bit"},
            {"D" : "Dirty Bit"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Dirty Bit"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 95,
        "Name" : "Question 95",
        "Question" : " During a write operation if the required block is not present in the cache then ______ occurs",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Write Miss"},
            {"B" : "Write Latency"},
            {"C" : "Write Hit"},
            {"D" : "Write Delay"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Write Miss"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 96,
        "Name" : "Question 96",
        "Question" : "While using the direct mapping technique, in a 16 bit system the higher order 5 bits are used for ________",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Id"},
            {"B" : "Word"},
            {"C" : "Tag"},
            {"D" : "Block"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Tag"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 97,
        "Name" : "Question 97",
        "Question" : "The bit used to indicate whether the block was recently used or not is _______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Reference Bit"},
            {"B" : "Dirty Bit"},
            {"C" : "Control Bit"},
            {"D" : "Idol Bit"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Dirty Bit"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 98,
        "Name" : "Question 98",
        "Question" : "The number successful accesses to memory stated as a fraction is called as ______",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Access Rate"},
            {"B" : "Success Rate"},
            {"C" : "Hit Rate"},
            {"D" : "Miss Rate"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Hit Rate"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 99,
        "Name" : "Question 99",
        "Question" : "For converting a virtual address into the physical address, the programs are divided into ________",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Pages"},
            {"B" : "Frames"},
            {"C" : "Segments"},
            {"D" : "Blocks"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Pages"
    },

    {
        "ID" : 100,
        "Name" : "Question 100",
        "Question" : "The fetch and execution cycles are interleaved with the help of ________",
        "Options" : [
            {"A" : "Modification In Processor Architecture"},
            {"B" : "Clock"},
            {"C" : "Special Unit"},
            {"D" : "Control Unit"}
        ],
        "Answer" : "Clock"
    }

]
